Finding Aid for the Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers File Listing
  - Academic Library Materials
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Bonn, George S. Literature of Science and Technology 1966 from reserve folder (Box 73, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Voress, Hugh E. Literature Searching Techniques 2 copies from reserve folders (Box 73, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Research and Notes, 1962, 1963, 1964 and 1965 (Box 73, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Research and Notes, 1966 and 1967 and Undated (Box 73, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Publications, 1952, 1962, 1964, 1965, 1966, and Undated (Box 73, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 506 Library in the Community Tentative Course Outline (Box 73, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 507 Public Library Administration Course Description (Box 73, File 13)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 514A Fieldwork Student Paper (Box 73, File 14)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 515A Information from Books Course Description (Box 73, File 15)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 515C Reference and Bibliography Syllabus and Notes from, 1946, 1947, and 1948 (Box 73, File 16)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 515C Reference and Bibliography Undated Syllabi and Notes (Box 73, File 17)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 515C Reference and Bibliography Publications (Box 74, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 517A Library in the Community Bibliography (Box 74, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Outline (Box 74, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Southern Library Schools Correspondence and Reports (Box 74, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Southern Library Conference on Education (Box 74, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Southeastern Conference on Library Education February 29-March 6, 1948 Conference Proceeding and Student Report (Box 74, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Southern Library Reports and Publications (Box 74, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Report on Progress and Problems in Training School Librarianship in the South (Box 74, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Two Student Reports on Special Libraries (Box 74, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Alabama- School Libraries (Box 74, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Arkansas- School Libraries Two Student Reports (Box 74, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Florida- School Libraries Student Report (Box 74, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Kentucky- School Libraries Correspondence, Student Paper, and Publications (Box 74, File 13)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Louisiana- School Libraries Publication and Student Paper (Box 74, File 14)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Mississippi- School Libraries (Box 74, File 15)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries North Carolina- School Libraries Correspondence, Three Student Papers, and Publications (Box 75, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- School Libraries Seven Student Papers (Box 75, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- School Libraries Newsletters and Publications (Box 75, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- School Libraries Publications (Box 75, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- School Libraries Publications (Box 75, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- Special Libraries Publications (Box 75, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- Special Libraries Publications (Box 75, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- Special Libraries Publications (Box 75, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Student Report on Tennessee Regional Library Service Bookmobile (Box 75, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- Special Informational Resources, Memphis (Box 75, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Tennessee- Special Informational Resources, Nashville (Box 75, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Texas- School Libraries (Box 75, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 544 Southern Libraries Virginia- School Libraries Three Student Papers (Box 76, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 552 Government Publications Course Description (Box 76, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 570 Instruction in the Use of the Library (Box 76, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 570 Organization of State University Reference Departments (544 Southern Libraries) (Box 76, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 570 Reference and Research Service Outline and Student Paper (Box 76, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 572 Reading Interests, Summer 1960 (Box 76, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials Advanced Reference and Research, December 1954 (Box 76, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials Courses Taught, June 1941-1972 (Box 76, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials Legal Bibliography (Box 76, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials Miscellaneous Notes (Box 76, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials Irish Libraries (Box 76, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Peabody Publications (Box 76, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School—Reference Curriculum (Box 76, File 13)
    - Peabody Library School-- Standardized Test Forms (Box 76, File 14)
    - Peabody Library School—Teaching Bibliography of Social Sciences (Box 76, File 15)
  - Publications Materials
  - Research Librarianship
    - Correspondence Outgoing- Louis Shore, Editor, February 1939-August 1941 (Box 76, File 16)
    - Correspondence Outgoing- Frances Cheney, Editor, September 1942-February 1943 (Box 76, File 17)
    - Correspondence Outgoing- Frances Cheney, Editor, March 1943-August 1944 (Box 76, File 18)
    - Correspondence Incoming- Frances Cheney, Editor Abbot, Etheldred- Greenberg, Emil (Box 77, File 1)
    - Correspondence Incoming- Frances Cheney, Editor Hansen, Agnes Camilla- Lynn, Jeanette (Box 77, File 2)
    - Correspondence Incoming- Frances Cheney, Editor Manley, Marian C., January 1941-April 1944 (Box 77, File 3)
    - Correspondence Incoming- Frances Cheney, Editor Manning, Ethelwyn- Windle, John T. (Box 77, File 4)
    - Outline and Publication on Medicine from Eileen Cunningham (Box 77, File 5)
    - Chapter on Legal Reference Materials and Methods written by Mile O. Price (Box 77, File 6)
    - Chapter on English Literature written by Guy Lyle (Box 77, File 7)
    - Chapter on Public Administration written by Lucile L. Keck (Box 77, File 8)
    - Bibliographic Outline and Procedures (Box 77, File 9)
  - Consultant Projects
    - South Texas Library System (Box 77, File 10)
    - Southern College Library Reference- Virginia Polytechnic Institute Reference (Georgia Faison) (Box 77, File 11)
    - Southern College Library Reference- Washington and Lee Reference (Georgia Faison) (Box 77, File 12)
    - Southern College Library Reference- William and Mary Reference (Box 77, File 13)
    - Southern College Library Reference- Women’s College of the University of North Carolina Reference (Georgia Faison) (Box 77, File 14)
    - Southern College Library Reference- Miscellaneous (Box 77, File 15)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Correspondence, 1946-1955 (Box 77, File 16)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, 1944-1947 (Box 77, File 17)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, 1948-1949 (Box 77, File 18)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, 1950-1952 (Box 77, File 19)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, January 1953-November 1953 (Box 77, File 20)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, January 1954-July 1954 (Box 77, File 21)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, August 1954-December 1954 (Box 77, File 22)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, January 1955-September 1956 (Box 78, File 1)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Organizational Materials; Memoranda, Statistics, Legislative Bills, Appropriations Requests, Newsletters, Administrative Materials, January 1957 (Box 78, File 2)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, General Information Packet compiled and stapled (Box 78, File 3)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Undated Materials Including a Tentative Manual for Regional Library Services (Box 78, File 4)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Maps Outlining Service Demographics by County 1939-1957 Incomplete (Box 78, File 5)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Speech by Miss Emma Watts January 31, 1928 to the Nashville Library Club “Library Extension Work In Tennessee” (Box 78, File 6)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Report on Library Service in Bledsoe County, Tennessee by Mary Elizabeth Cole (Box 78, File 7)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Scripts from 1948 Radio Broadcast and 1952 “The Common Heritage” filmstrip (Box 78, File 8)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Publications, 1944-1953 (Box 78, File 9)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Publications, 1954- 1958 and Undated (Box 78, File 10)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Clippings (Box 78, File 11)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Undated Miscellaneous Notes (Box 78, File 12)
    - Tennessee Regional Library Service, Information from other States (Box 78, File 13)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital, Patient Library Evaluation (Box 78, File 14)
  - Library Organizations
    - Association of American Library Schools Midwinter Meeting February 2, 1954 plus additional materials (Box 78, File 15)
    - American Library Association (Box 78, File 16)
    - American Library Association Midwinter Meeting, February 2-4 1954 (Box 78, File 17)
    - American Library Association Midwinter Meeting, January 28, 1957 (Box 78, File 18)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Blank Survey Forms (Box 78, File 19)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Correspondence, Outgoing, August 15, 1956-March 31, 1959 (Box 78, File 20)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Correspondence, Outgoing, January 30, 1960-February 19, 1962 (Box 78, File 21)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Correspondence, Incoming Armstrong, Julia Ruth- Higgins, Charles (Box 78, File 22)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Correspondence, Incoming Mitchell, Mary- Wheeler, Joseph and Unidentified (Box 79, File 1)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey “Reference Service in American Public Libraries Serving Populations of 10,000 or more: A Report of a Nationwide Survey”, June 1960 (Box 79, File 2)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey “Public Library Reference Service in the United States- A Survey” (Box 79, File 3)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey “Public Library Reference Service in the United States-A Survey” Draft, Notes and Progress Reports (Box 79, File 4)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Research, Notes, and Publications (Box 79, File 5)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Publications of Peripheral Importance (Box 79, File 6)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Partial Survey Results, June 20, 1956 (Box 79, File 7)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey National Result (Box 79, File 8)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- New England (Box 79, File 9)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results-Middle Atlantic States (Box 79, File 10)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- East North Central (Box 79, File 11)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- East South Central (Box 79, File 12)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- West North Central (Box 79, File 13)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- West South Central (Box 79, File 14)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- Mountain (Box 79, File 15)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey Regional Results- Pacific (Box 79, File 16)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Alabama (Box 79, File 17)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Arkansas (Box 79, File 18)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Arizona (Box 79, File 19)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- California (Box 79, File 20)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Colorado (Box 80, File 1)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Connecticut (Box 80, File 2)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Delaware (Box 80, File 3)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- District of Columbia (Box 80, File 4)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Florida (Box 80, File 5)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Georgia (Box 80, File 6)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Idaho (Box 80, File 7)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Illinois (Box 80, File 8)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Indiana (Box 80, File 9)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Iowa (Box 80, File 10)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Kansas (Box 80, File 11)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Kentucky (Box 80, File 12)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Louisiana (Box 80, File 13)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Maine (Box 80, File 14)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Maryland (Box 80, File 15)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Massachusetts (Box 80, File 16)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Michigan (Box 80, File 17)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Minnesota (Box 80, File 18)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Mississippi (Box 81, File 1)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Missouri (Box 81, File 2)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Montana (Box 81, File 3)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Nebraska (Box 81, File 4)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Nevada (Box 81, File 5)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey-New Hampshire (Box 81, File 6)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- New Jersey (Box 81, File 7)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- New Mexico (Box 81, File 8)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- New York (Box 81, File 9)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- North Carolina (Box 81, File 10)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- North Dakota (Box 81, File 11)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Ohio (Box 81, File 12)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Oklahoma (Box 81, File 13)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Oregon (Box 81, File 14)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Pennsylvania (Box 81, File 15)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Rhode Island (Box 81, File 16)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- South Carolina (Box 81, File 17)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- South Dakota (Box 81, File 18)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Tennessee (Box 82, File 1)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Texas (Box 82, File 2)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Utah (Box 82, File 3)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Vermont (Box 82, File 4)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Virginia (Box 82, File 5)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Washington (Box 82, File 6)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- West Virginia (Box 82, File 7)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Wisconsin (Box 82, File 8)
    - American Library Association Reference Services Division Public Library Reference Survey- Wyoming (Box 82, File 9)
    - American Library Association Subscription Book Committee, 1960-1963 (Box 82, File 10)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries (Box 82, File 11)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries, Expenditures (Box 82, File 12)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries, General Statement (Box 82, File 13)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries, Midwinter report to ALA (Box 82, File 14)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries, Photos and Clippings (Box 82, File 15)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries, Publications (Box 83, File 1)
    - American Library Association U.S. Field Seminar on Library Reference Services for Japanese Libraries, Reports (Box 83, File 2)
    - Association of College and Research Libraries (Box 83, File 3)
    - Canadian Library Association (Box 83, File 4)
    - Catholic Library Association (Box 83, File 5)
    - Japanese Library Association (Box 83, File 6)
    - Japanese Library Association (Box 83, File 7)
    - Japanese Library Association, Japan Library Law and Regulations (Box 83, File 8)
    - Japanese Library Association, 60th Anniversary Celebration (Box 83, File 9)
    - Nashville Library Club (Box 83, File 10)
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (Box 83, File 11)
    - Southeastern Library Association (Box 83, File 12)
    - Tennessee Library Association, Press Releases for TLA Publication (Box 83, File 13)
    - Tennessee Library Association, Reorganization Committee; Correspondence, September 1950-December 1950 (Box 83, File 14)
    - Tennessee Library Association, Reorganization Committee; Memoranda, Notes, Legislative Bills, Reports, Conference Materials, Speeches, 1947-1952 and Undated (Box 83, File 15)
    - Tennessee Library Association, Reorganization Committee: Clippings (Box 84, File 1)
  - Subject Files
    - American and Japanese Relations (Box 84, File 2)
    - Bibliographies and Lists—Bibliographical Methods, bibliography (Box 84, File 3)
    - Bibliographies and Lists--Catalogue of the Southern Newspaper Library (Box 84, File 4)
    - Bibliographies and Lists—Final Periodical Rating, 1951 (Box 84, File 5)